Toh Hong Xiang

Self-driven and dependable web developer with 1 year experience, familiar in conducting analysis to pinpoint effective solutions for various end-users. Quick in adapting unfamiliar technologies to deliver impactful products ahead of deadlines. Focused on creating an intuitive, problem-free user experience. Strong interest in web development, data science, and robotics.

Singapore +65 9431 7592 tohhongxiang@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Industrial Electronics Pte Ltd, Software Developer

Dec 2019 - July 2020

- Designed and implemented new features to for an e-commerce web application to track and trade warehouse stocks
- Developed a Drag-&-Drop template builder for websites
- Implemented smooth UI/UX, delivering consistent results ahead of schedule
- Demonstrated high levels of initiative by spotting potential bugs ahead of time, constant code refactoring

Singapore Armed Forces, Admin Support Assistant

Aug 2019 - Oct 2019

- Built a small web application to help the management of large complicated menus within SAF Cookhouses
- Implemented website using MongoDB, Express, React and Node
- Focused on clear and intuitive user interfaces to cater to the technologically unfamiliar market
- Significantly lowered error rates by 80%, and improved efficiency by 20%
- Demo and Code

FEATURED PROJECTS

NextJS Notes and Blog Website

- File-based blog and notes website using NextJS with markdown
- Includes TailwindCSS for styling
- Demo and Code

NextIS ECommerce Website

- Built with NextJS, Directus CMS, TailwindCSS, Snipcart
- Fully featured CMS for clients to add/delete/update products
- Fully functional store for customers to purchase items from the store
- <u>Demo</u> and <u>Code</u>

"Stumblr" Social Media Website — Tumblr Clone

- Uses PostgreSQL, Node, Express, React
- Tumblr Clone, features basic CRUD and user authentication
- <u>Demo</u> and <u>Code</u>

LINKS

Portfolio

https://personalblog-tohhongxiang123.vercel.app/abo

Github

https://github.com/tohhongxiang123

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/i n/toh-hong-xiang-3155111 8b/

SKILLS

Front-End

- HTML, CSS
- Javascript
- React (With redux)
- React Native
- Vue
- Bootstrap
- SCSS
- jQuery
- API

Back-End

- NodeJS
- Typescript
- Express
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- GraphQL/REST
- TypeORM

Miscellaneous

- Version Control (Git)
- Github Actions (CI/CD)
- Photoshop/Figma
- Heroku
- Python

Gallereddit — Gallery Visualizer for Reddit

- Uses React and Express
- Data pulled using Reddit and Imgur API
- Features OAuth2 to connect web application to reddit users
- <u>Demo</u> and <u>Code</u>

EDUCATION

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

July 2020 - July 2024

Currently studying for a Bachelor of Computer Science

Anderson Junior College, Singapore

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

H2 Physics, H2 Math, H2 Chemistry and H1 Economics, with an additional H3 Math. Scored 90 rank points in GCE 'A' Levels 2018

Kuo Chuan Presbyterian Secondary School, Singapore

Jan 2012 - Dec 2015

Vice-president of the Robotics Team. Participated in various competitions such as National Robotics Challenge, holding training sessions for team members.